cineplex.com 2018-05-14

# Cineplex.com | Privacy Policy

### Cineplex Entertainment LP: Guest Privacy Policy (the "Privacy Policy")

**Effective Date:** April 23, 2018

At Cineplex Entertainment LP, we share your concerns about the privacy and protection of your personal information. This Privacy Policy describes the steps we have taken and our practices regarding the protection of your personal information. Personal information is information about an identifiable individual ("Personal Information") including, without limitation, such information as your name, address, birth date, and personal contact information and other information as described below.

This Privacy Policy applies to Cineplex Entertainment LP and its wholly owned subsidiaries, affiliates, and related entities (collectively, “Cineplex” or “our”, “we”, or “us”). The contents of this Privacy Policy are intended to be read and understood in accordance and compliance with all applicable privacy laws, statutes, and regulations in the jurisdictions where Cineplex operates.

If you have not already done so, we encourage you to familiarize yourself with this Privacy Policy before using any Cineplex website or mobile application (collectively the "Websites"), purchasing Cineplex products or services, or applying for an employment opportunity with Cineplex. The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform our visitors, guests, job applicants, customers and other individuals with whom we deal ("you" and "your") about how we collect, use, disclose and protect Personal Information. This Privacy Policy applies to the collection, use, disclosure and protection of your Personal Information by Cineplex. Your dealings with Cineplex and all of its associated brands (Cineplex Cinemas, Cineplex Odeon, Famous Players, Galaxy, SilverCity, StarCité, Colossus, Coliseum, Colisée, Scotiabank Theatre, Cinema City, and The Rec Room) are also governed by this Privacy Policy.

Your use of our Websites is further governed under the applicable Terms of Use as indicated on such Websites.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or about our practices with respect to Personal Information, or if you wish us to stop communicating with you, or if you wish us to delete your Personal Information, please notify us:

  * by email at privacy@cineplex.com
  * telephone us at 1-877-323-6645
  * or by mail at:

1303 Yonge Street   
Toronto, ON M4T 2Y9  _Attn: Chief Privacy Officer_

**Personal Information We Collect**

Cineplex and its employees, agents, contractors, service providers, partners and representatives may collect the following Personal Information:

  * **Contact Information** (e.g. name, home address, home or mobile telephone number or e-mail address);
  * **Credit or Debit Card Information, including card number, expiry date and 3 digit CVS code** (e.g. when purchasing theatre tickets or other products or services);
  * **Information relevant to a particular service you request** (e.g. the age and gender of a child or other person where you request our birthday party services);
  * **Survey Responses  **(e.g. when you provide your name or other contract information in order to take advantage of various benefits for participating in a survey, or when you consent to us contacting you about your comments);
  * **Preferences and other Personal Information provided by you on our  ** **Websites** (e.g. including but not limited to local theatre preferences, favourite movie genres, movie reviews, and comments);
  * **Job Applications** (e.g. information you provide to us when applying for an employment opportunity: (i) by sending us a resume; (ii) by submitting a job application on our Websites; or (iii) by submitting a job application through the website of an authorized third party service provider).

**Use of Your Personal Information**

We collect and use Personal Information for a number of purposes:

  * **Purchases made by you:** Personal contact and credit/debit card information will be used by Cineplex to process your purchases and reservations (for example, ticket purchase made through our Websites or at one of our theatres, products and services purchased at The Rec Room® special event bookings at Cineplex theatre or The Rec Room, or the purchase or rental of movies through the Cineplex Store). For event bookings, such as birthday parties, the child's name, age and gender will be used to organize the event. In these cases, credit/debit card information is only used for the purposes required to process and complete the transaction and/or service requested by you, and is only retained in transaction records required for internal management and auditing purposes or as otherwise required by law, unless you are informed otherwise or you provide your consent.
  * **Theatre and The Rec Room Administration:** Your name, address and telephone number will be stored by us should you provide such information when you use our lost-and-found services. Also, your name, address and telephone number may be collected and used by Cineplex for audit and refund verification purposes when you request a ticket refund. We may require identification to be provided to establish a person's age for age-restricted movies, events or activities (such as virtual reality games), age restricted ticket purchases or access to our VIP cinemas, or the purchase of alcohol.
  * **Video Surveillance:** Cineplex monitors its premises, electronically and otherwise, for crime deterrence and detection purposes, to which you implicitly consent when you visit our theatres or The Rec Room. In the event of accident or theft, Cineplex may collect, use and disclose information related to the incident or theft as required for operational, insurance, legal or other necessary purposes.
  * **Contests/Benefits:** Cineplex runs contests, in our theatres, at The Rec Room, or with our various business partners and third party advertising clients through our Websites. We may request your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address and we may also require proof of age for the purposes of determining eligibility.  Unless otherwise stated in the applicable contest rules, or if you provide your consent, your Personal Information will only be used for prize notification and fulfilment and related purposes in connection with the contest. Contact information may be required to administer other benefits our visitors and /or guests have requested or accepted.\
  * **Surveys:** Your participation in such surveys or market research is entirely voluntary and, in some cases, you may be able to participate anonymously. Your contact information, including your name, address, telephone number and/or other Personal Information may be required: (1) to permit you to enjoy bonuses or benefits which may be available to survey or market research participants (in which case your contact information will only be used for notification or fulfillment purposes); or (2) where you have provided your express consent to us contacting you to discuss comments that you made during our surveys and/or market research. Except as described in this Privacy Policy, survey and/or research responses are only used by Cineplex on an aggregate basis.
  * **Other Uses:** We may also use Personal Information, where necessary, for:

o establishing, maintaining and/or fulfilling relationships with our business partners, third-party vendors of products and/or services, as well as our corporate and business customers;

o evaluating job applications or resumes which are sent to us, as further described in the Job Application section below;

o conducting operating, administering and otherwise managing our business, to satisfy legal, regulatory, security, audit, financial and processing requirements, or as otherwise permitted or required by law.

**Disclosure of Personal Information**

Personal Information collected by Cineplex is not disclosed to other parties, except as follows:

  * We may share your Personal Information with outside parties who sponsor or otherwise participate in sweepstakes or other promotions, whether on our Websites or otherwise. However, we will not share your Personal Information with these parties except with your express consent and in accordance with this Privacy Policy.
  * Cineplex may contract with third parties, such as other companies, individuals, contractors, and/or other entities, without limitation, to perform certain technical functions on our behalf. For instance, we may use such third parties to host message boards, user forums or webpages, to develop software applications and create and maintain databases, or send and receive communications on our behalf. Your Personal Information may be disclosed to such third party companies, individuals, contractors and/or other entities, without limitation, in the ordinary course of our business operations.
  * All Cineplex employees, agents, contractors, service providers, partners and representatives who have access to your Personal Information are required to protect the information in a manner that is consistent with this and any other Cineplex Privacy Policy, other policy and/or procedure, in effect from time to time.
  * Your Personal Information may be disclosed to our parent, subsidiary, affiliated and/or related corporations or entities, or to their employees, agents, contractors, representatives, servants, legal counsel and/or accountants without limitation, for operational, management and administrative purposes, as well as internal audit, legal, regulatory, security, insurance, financial, processing and other purposes, or as otherwise permitted or required by law. Personal Information may also be transferred to certain other entities, whether subsidiary, related or affiliated entitles to Cineplex or otherwise, where such entities provide administrative, management, operational, processing, support or other services to us, in which case we take steps to ensure that your Personal Information is protected and not used or disclosed for any purpose except: (i) as directed by Cineplex; (ii) as permitted by this Privacy Policy; (iii) for which you are deemed to consent under the terms of this Privacy Policy; and/or (iv) as permitted or required by law.

In addition, Cineplex may transfer Personal Information to outside agents, contractors, service providers or mandataries who perform services on our behalf (e.g. vendors’ fulfilment houses, survey, market research and contest service providers etc.), in which case we use contractual or other means to ensure that your Personal Information is protected and not used or disclosed for any purpose except: (i) as directed by Cineplex; (ii) as permitted by this Privacy Policy; and/or (iii) as permitted or required by law.

Your Personal Information may be used by Cineplex and disclosed to parties connected with the contemplated or actual financing, insuring, sale, assignment or other disposal of all or part of Cineplex's business or assets, including for the purposes of permitting such parties to determine whether to proceed or continue with such transaction or business relationship, to fulfill reporting, audit, legal and/or other requirements or, in the case of sale or assignment, the use and disclosure by those parties for substantially the same purposes as described in this Privacy Policy.

Cineplex may also disclose Personal Information as necessary to meet legal, audit, regulatory, insurance, security or other requirements. Cineplex does not disclose your Personal Information except: (i) as permitted by this Privacy Policy; (ii) where you have provided express consent for us to do so; and/or (iii) as permitted or required by law.

**The Websites and the Internet**

The Websites have primary worldwide web address(es) (also known as the "uniform resource locator" or "URL") and consist of various individual webpages, which are owned and/or operated by Cineplex. The Websites consist of all content thereon and all other domain names, worldwide web addresses, uniform resource locators, URL’s and webpages which are solely owned and/or operated by Cineplex, and which link or otherwise connect to the Websites. The following Websites are not governed by this Privacy Policy: SCENE.ca, WorldGaming.com, and WinWithP1AG.com. On the Websites, visitors may conduct activities where Personal Information is required or may be provided, including but not limited to: registering to receive customized information, entering contests, participating in polls or surveys or purchasing products and/or services. Cineplex does not collect Personal Information about you unless you choose to provide us with such information for such purposes or activities.

_Regarding External Links:_  As a convenience to you and other visitors, the Websites contain links to a number of third party websites or third party webpages. These third party websites and webpages are not owned or controlled by Cineplex and this Privacy Policy does not apply to such websites or webpages. Should you decide to navigate to any websites or webpage external to the Websites, you do so entirely at your own risk. External links to third party websites or webpages accessed through our Websites, as well as the content on such third party websites or webpages, are not investigated, assured, guaranteed, verified, monitored, recommended or endorsed by Cineplex. Cineplex provides these links merely as a convenience to you and to other visitors to our  Websites, and the inclusion of such links does not imply that we endorse or recommend such websites or webpages. We specifically disclaim any liability, obligation or responsibility whatsoever for the content or use of such third party websites or webpages.

Please note that the online purchase of theatre tickets through third party websites or services may be governed by terms and conditions and privacy practices as set by such third party website or service. Third party websites and services are not within the scope of this Privacy Policy and Cineplex expressly disclaims any liability, obligation or responsibility whatsoever for the content or use of such third party websites or services.

We use information which you provide to us on the Websites to facilitate your registration, to understand the identity of our guests and the nature of their preferences, to improve the content of the Websites, to customize the content and/or layout of our webpages for each visitor based on the information provided to us, to send you periodic newsletters and mailings that you request, to process your purchases and to conduct surveys, polls and contests. Cineplex does not disclose Personal Information contained in our subscriber database to any third parties except: (i) as permitted by this Privacy Policy; (ii) where you have otherwise provided express consent for us to do so; and/or (iii) as permitted or required by law.

Individuals who provide us with their telephone numbers will only receive communications from us with respect to orders, contests or other products or services that they have requested, unless they provide express consent to receive telephone calls or SMS messages from us. If you make inquiries of Cineplex directly by e-mail, or through our Websites, these inquiries are forwarded to the relevant department and are not used for other purposes, or stored (other than maintaining a record of our correspondence with you).

**Unsubscribe / Deletion Requests**

E-Mail and SMS messages

Receiving e-mail and SMS messages from us is optional and you may unsubscribe at any time by (a) following the unsubscribe link in any email or SMS message; (b) changing your communication preferences through your Cineplex Connect and/or SCENE® account (if applicable); or (c) contacting us

  * by email at privacy@cineplex.com
  * telephone us at 1-877-323-6645
  * or by mail at:

1303 Yonge Street   
Toronto, ON M4T 2Y9  _Attn: Chief Privacy Officer_

Mail

If you provide us with your mailing address, you may receive periodic mailings from us, or our business partners, with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mail from us, please change your preferences on the Websites, or contact us as indicated at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

Online Profile

When you register for a Cineplex Connect account on our Websites, make purchases, enter contests, respond to surveys, or otherwise participate in our online community, our servers may store your Personal Information, contact details or other information in order to facilitate site login, the automatic completion of forms and otherwise for your convenience. If you prefer that we not store such information on our servers, you may select the appropriate option on the Websites (if that option is available) or you may contact us as indicated at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

If you wish your registration profile to be entirely deleted from our servers, you may contact us as indicated at the beginning of this Privacy Policy.

Information Storage

The nature of internet browsing is such that this activity passively and automatically collects and discloses certain information about each individual’s use of the internet. This information may be associated with an individual’s Internet Protocol ("IP") address. This is a unique internet "address" which is assigned to all internet users by their Internet Service Provider ("ISP"). Our server logs record statistical information, such as visitors' IP addresses, type of operating systems, time and duration of visit, webpages requested, as well as identifying categories of visitors by items such as domains and browser types.

**Cookies and Behavioural Advertising**

Our Websites makes use of both "sessional" and "persistent" cookies. Cookies are small text files offered to your computer by Web servers in order to keep track of your browser settings as you navigate the site. Persistent cookies are stored on your hard drive. Sessional cookies are stored in temporary (cache) memory and are deleted when you shut down your browser or turn off your computer. We use cookies to store your preferences, record session information such as language preferences, record user-specific information on what pages you access or visit, develop information about your preferences and interests, alert you to areas that we think might be of interest to you when you return to our site, record past activity in order to provide better service when you return to our site, help rotate banner advertising so as to ensure that visitors are not repeatedly sent the same banner ads, and customize Websites content based on your browser type or other information you provide.

For each visit to our Websites, cookies may be used by our server to recognize you where you have indicated your preference to be automatically logged in.

You may disable cookies using your browser's settings. Please consult your browser's help function for information on how to disable cookies. Note that if you disable cookies, certain features of our Websites will not function to their fullest potential.

To try and bring you offers that are of interest to you, Cineplex or its service providers place ads on our webpages. As a result of your visit to our site, or by clicking on these ads, we may collect passive information such as your domain type, your IP address and clickstream information.

On our Websites we store subscriber and password information in a secure manner not accessible to Web browsers, behind password protection, or off-line. We endeavor to use industry-standard encryption technologies when transferring and receiving consumer data exchanged with our Websites.

Some of the ads on our Websites are served through one or more reputable ad-serving companies, including but not limited to Google.  These third parties may use non-personal information, such as webpages you visit and cookies, to provide ads that may be of interest to you.   In addition, we may use IP addresses to allow our third party advertising partners to display more targeted ads and content.  This process does not include the use of your personal information, nor do we share your personal information with these ad-serving companies. 

Cineplex respects your right to control your advertising preferences. We are a member of the Interactive Advertising Bureau of Canada (IAB Canada), and we follow industry standards for online behavioural advertising, including standards set by the Digital Advertising Alliance Canada (DAAC).  DAAC’s Ad Choices initiative allows you to opt-out from the use of your online activities for the purpose of serving ads based on your internet browsing history.  Clicking on the Ad Choices logo on any ad will allow you to opt-out of online behavioural advertising from that advertiser.  However, please note, Ad Choices uses cookies to work and it is specific to the browser you are using at the time.  The services and tools provided by Ad Choices and the DAAC are provided by third parties and not Cineplex.  We do not control or operate these services or tools.  For more information about how you can manage your ad preference and control cookies please visit http://youradchoices.ca/

**Job Applicants  **

We may collect and use your Personal Information or any information you provide to us when you apply for a job, such as your previous employers, education, professional accreditations, or work experience (collectively, “Applicant Information”), whether you send us a resume; submit a job application on our Websites; or submit a job application through a third party website.  Your Personal Information and Applicant Information may be used to make hiring decisions, and to comply with applicable laws.  Should you be hired, relevant portions of your Personal Information will be used to create and maintain your employment records.   By providing Applicant Information, you agree that we may contract the employers, organizations, schools, professional associations provided by you, to verify the accuracy of such information. 

All Personal Information and Applicant Information provided by you and during the application process must be true, complete and correct to the best of your knowledge.  Any misrepresentation or omission of facts may result in refusal to hire or, if hired, may result in your dismissal at any time regardless of when the false answer or omissions are discovered.

By applying for a job with us, you hereby authorize Cineplex to thoroughly investigate your background, references, employment record and other matters related to your suitability for employment.  You further authorize persons, schools, my current employer (if applicable), and previous employers and organizations contacted by Cineplex Entertainment LP to provide any relevant information regarding my current and/or previous employment and thereby release all persons, schools, employers of any and all claims for providing such information.  You understand that you may be required to sign a confidentiality and/or non-competition agreement should you become an employee of Cineplex Entertainment LP.  You understand that nothing contained in your job application, or conveyed during any interview which may be granted, is intended to create an employment contract.  You understand that submitting a job application does not indicate there is a position open and does not obligate Cineplex Entertainment LP to hire you.

**Your Consent**

Consent to the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information may be given in various ways. Consent may be express (e.g. orally, electronically or on a form you may sign describing the intended uses and disclosures of Personal Information) or implied (e.g. when you provide information necessary for a service you have requested (such as providing us with your name, phone number and/or email for use by our lost and found services), or in some circumstances where notice has been provided to you about our intentions with respect to your Personal Information and you have not withdrawn your consent for an identified purpose, such as by using an "opt-out" option. Consent may be given by your authorized representative (such as a legal guardian, person having a power of attorney or a mandatary). By providing us with Personal Information, we will deem you to understand this Privacy Policy, and we will deem you to consent to our collection, use and disclosure of such Personal Information for the purposes identified or described in this Privacy Policy, if applicable, or otherwise at the time of collection. You may withdraw your consent to our collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information at any time, subject to contractual and legal restrictions and reasonable notice. Note that if you withdraw your consent to certain uses of your Personal Information, we may no longer be able to provide you with certain of our products or services.

Cineplex does not disclose your Personal Information except: (i) as permitted by this Privacy Policy; (ii) where you have provided express consent for us to do so; and/or (iii) as permitted or required by law. However, Cineplex may be required or permitted under statute, regulation or as otherwise at law or in equity to collect, use or disclose Personal Information without your consent (for example, in response to a court order or subpoena, or to comply with local or federal regulations, or to collect a debt owed to us).

**Security**

We protect your Personal Information using physical, electronic or procedural security measures as are appropriate and proportional to the sensitivity of the information in our custody or control, including safeguards to protect Personal Information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification. Cineplex and its employees, agents, contractors, legal, accounting or other service providers, partners, representatives and mandataries who require access to your Personal Information in order to fulfill their job requirements will have access to your Personal Information. You transmit or provide all Personal Information entirely at your own risk.

**Consent to Transfer**

Cineplex's Websites are operated on equipment located in Canada. If you are located in the United States of America, European Union or elsewhere outside Canada, please be aware that any information you provide to us will be transferred to Canada. By visiting the Websites, purchasing our products or services, participating in our online community and/or providing us with your Personal Information, you consent to this transfer. Regardless of your location, we shall protect your Personal Information using physical, electronic or procedural security measures as are appropriate and proportional to the sensitivity of the information in our custody or control, including safeguards to protect Personal Information against loss or theft, as well as unauthorized access, disclosure, copying, use, or modification. Please note that the Personal Information which you provide to us will be held and used in accordance with such Canadian federal or provincial laws as exist from time to time, and as are applicable.

**Note to Parents - Children's Privacy**

Protecting children's privacy is important to us. For that reason, we do not collect information on our Websites from those children we actually know are under 13 years of age. In addition, no part of our Websites are targeted to attract anyone under 13 years of age. We request that children under 13 years of age do not disclose or provide any Personal Information. If we discover such information, we will delete the child's Personal Information from our records. If for any reason we believe a user may be under the age of 13 we reserve the right to request proof of age of such user. If such proof is not provided, or if it is discovered a user is under the age of 13 all Personal Information of that user shall be deleted from our servers and associated systems and we reserve the right to limit and/or ban such user from our Websites. Notwithstanding the foregoing, Cineplex may from time to time conduct, sponsor, co-sponsor or participate in contests and/or promotions which may be open to entrants of all ages, including children under the age of 13. During such contests and/or promotions Cineplex makes special efforts to encourage children to consult with their parents before providing Personal Information and in each case parental consent must be obtained in order for any such entry or participation to be valid. Cineplex also believes that parents should supervise their children's online activities and consider using parental control tools, available from online services and software manufacturers, to help provide a child-friendly online environment. These tools may also prevent children from disclosing online their name, address, and other Personal Information without parental permission. For additional information about parental control tools, please visit [http://www.icra.org/_en/parents.](http://www.icra.org/)

**Policy Changes**

This Privacy Policy may be revised from time to time as Cineplex deems necessary or advisable in its sole discretion. If we materially change our privacy practices, we shall notify you of such changes on our Websites; if necessary, we shall also update our Privacy Policy as it appears on our Websites. If our information practices change such that your privacy may be materially affected, we shall notify you of such changes on our Websites; if necessary, we shall also update our Privacy Policy as it appears on our Websites. You will continue to have the ability to opt out of new non-essential uses or disclosures. If you are concerned with how your Personal Information is used, we encourage you to bookmark this site and to periodically review our Privacy Policy, or contact us as described below to obtain a current copy of our Privacy Policy.

**Access, Correction and Contacting Us**

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, or about our practices with respect to Personal Information, or if you wish us to stop communicating with you, or if you wish us to delete your Personal Information from our database, please notify us:

  * by email at [privacy@cineplex.com](mailto:privacy@cineplex.com)
  * telephone us at 1-877-323-6645
  * or by mail at:

1303 Yonge Street   
Toronto, ON M4T 2Y9  _Attn: Chief Privacy Officer_

Please clearly indicate the information that you wish to review or have changed. We will to reply to your request as soon as reasonably possible.

© Cineplex Entertainment LP
